apologeticspress.org 2005-04-04

# Apologetics Press

|   
Copyright Notice | Usage Guidelines | Privacy Statement

Effective January 1, 2001

**Information Collection and Use**

Apologetics Press, Inc. (“AP”) is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from that which is disclosed in this statement. AP collects information from our users at several different points on our Web site, as detailed below.

**User-Provided Information**

We request information from the user on our order form. Here a user must provide contact information (such as name and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customers’ orders. If we have trouble processing an order, this information may be used to contact the user.

If a user wishes to receive a free copy of _Reason & Revelation_ or _Discovery_ , we ask for name, mailing address, and e-mail address on our sample request form. We use this information to provide the requested sample, or to contact the user should a problem arise in sending the sample issue.

**Log Files**

When users visit our site, we automatically collect certain information that is not connected to an identified individual. This may include the type of computer operating system (e.g., Windows or Mac OS), browser (e.g., Netscape, Internet Explorer, etc.), Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, and pages visited. We use this information only in the aggregate to analyze site usage, and to improve the design and content of our site.

An IP address is the unique electronic address of a computer attached to the Internet. However, AP does not link such addresses to personally identifiable information that can be used to recognize, contact, or locate the person to whom such information pertains.

However, placing and order through the WebStore will place information such as billing and shipping addresses into a repository database for shopping convenience. Credit card information is not stored on our server for your protection.

**Registration**

No registration is required to use this Web site. 

**Cookies**

Cookies are stored by us on a user’s computer in the event that the user selcets items on the subscription form. The information contained in the cookie is: 

  * A **cart number** to maintain the contents of the shopping cart (stored on our secure server for few hours) 
  * An **ID number** to temporarily remember shipping, not billing, information (also stored on our secure server for few hours) 

The cookie itself does not contain any personal information.

**“In-House” Promotional Offers**

AP does not make offers to the _Reason & Revelation_ or _Discovery_ subscription list that are not directly related to those subscriptions.

_Reason & Revelation_ or _Discovery_ givers occasionally will receive information on other products and services of AP. These “givers” are customers who have bought a subscription to either journal for another person, and who also wish to receive future renewal notices related to that subscription. Givers can elect to have their information excluded from such promotional offers. 

We do not use contact information provided on our sample request form, other than to mail the requested sample or to contact the user should a problem arise in meeting that request.

**Sharing of Information**

We do not share any contact information from our _Discovery_ subscriber list.

On rare occasions, we may exchange the names and addresses of _Reason & Revelation_ and _Discovery_ givers and/or _Reason & Revelation_ subscribers with like-minded organizations. Givers and subscribers can elect to have such information excluded from such sharing arrangements. 

We use a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services, and we use other companies to ship orders. These companies do not retain, share, store, or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

We do not share aggregated demographic information collected from this site with third parties.

**Privacy on Externally Linked Sites**

The current privacy statement applies solely to information collected by us on this Web site.

Our site contains links to external sites not associated with AP. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of those sites. We encourage users to read the privacy statements of each and every site that collects personally identifiable information.

**Security**

This Web site takes every precaution to protect our users’ information. When you submit sensitive information via our site, that information is protected both on-line and off-line.

When our sample request and order forms ask users to enter sensitive information (such as credit card numbers), that information is protected by Secure Sockets Layer (“SSL”) — the industry-standard method for protecting Web communications. However, to take advantage of this feature you must be using a browser that supports SSL, such as the more recent versions of Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer. You know you have a secure connection on these browsers when the padlock icon is closed, or the key icon is complete (depending on the browser client and version you are using). 

To protect sensitive information off-line, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access, maintain data security, and correctly use the information we collect on-line.

If you have any questions about the security of our Web site, you may contact us in any of the following ways.

**Call:** 334-272-8558, or 800-234-8558  
**Fax:** 334-270-2002, or 800-234-2882  
**E-mail:** [mail@apologeticspress.org](mailto:mail@apologeticspress.org)  
**Write:** Apologetics Press, 230 Landmark Drive, Montgomery, AL 36117-2752, USA.

Our office hours are 8 a.m. to 5 p.m., Central Standard Time.

**Supplementation of Information**

We do not supplement the information we receive with information from third-party sources. “Supplementation” is a way for companies to learn more about users by linking personally identifiable information with data collected by other agencies (e.g., credit report services).

**Correcting/Updating Personal Information**

If a customer’s personally identifiable information changes, or if a subscriber wishes to cancel his or her subscription, we will endeavor to correct, update, or remove the information that was provided to us. Subscribers should direct their requests to our offices (see contact information above).

**Policies For Kids Under 13 Years of Age**

AP encourages parents and guardians to spend time on-line with their children, and to participate in the activities offered on this site.

Users under the age of 13 should not submit any personally identifiable information without the consent of their parent or guardian. Children must have a parent call us (at 800-234-8558) before they submit such information.

The names and addresses of users who are under 13, and who submit personal information once parental consent is verified, are not retained by AP any longer than is necessary. We do not use this information for any purpose other than to meet their requests, or to contact them should a problem arise in meeting those requests.

Customers may request that our publication, _Discovery_ , be sent in the name of a child. This name and the corresponding address are stored off-line in our mailing list database. We use this list only in the maintenance of these subscriptions. We do not share this mailing list with any third party for any purpose whatsoever.

**Notification of Changes**

We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will put a notice to that effect on our Web Site's home page. If at any point we decide to use the personally identifiable information of our customers in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify our customers by mail. Customers will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner.

|
